#### **Lambert Parassi**

P.O. Box 530-80109, Mtwapa, Kenya Cell Phone: +254716163368

Email: parassilambert@hotmail.com

#### **Professional Profile**

I'm a proactive graduate electrical engineer with significant experience in electrical design, testing, analysis, and electrical project coordination and implementation. I have a strong adherence to safety, ability to work well as a team member, and I also have exceptional work ethics. I have an eye for details coupled with proven technical and interpersonal communications skills.

## **Objective**

My aspiration is to be a reputable Electrical Engineer in an esteemed organization and eventually consultancy along the same line through embracing sound Engineering practices.

# Core competencies and professional strength include:

- Competencies in the upkeep, diagnosis and repair of electrical circuits and wiring.
- Good understanding of Electrical Drawings.
- Electrical Products Testing / Analysis.
- Designing and simulating electronic circuit schematic using Proteus 8.0.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**25<sup>th</sup> August, 2014 - to date** - Arm Engineering Co Ltd.

#### Responsibilities (Electrical Technician):

 Testing and Commissioning of Current Transformers (CT) this entailed Ratio, Magnetization Characteristic, Polarity and Insulation Test.

- Simple relay configuration to automate various functions in a substation such as remote tripping to isolate a fault.
- Circuit breaker testing and commissioning this entailed manual tripping and closing testing, electrical closing and tripping, remote, local test, interlock tests, Auto-reclose test.
- Generator maintenance by checking the oil levels to prevent overheating.
- Checking the Generator fuel level to ensure uninterrupted power to essential loads in the substation control room in case of power loss in the main power supply line.

**5<sup>th</sup> May, 2014 to 31<sup>st</sup> July, 2014 -** Kenya Electricity Generating Company Limited (KenGen) in the Project Execution Department.

#### **Responsibilities (Intern):**

Project Name: 4 x 70 MW Olkaria 1AU and Olkaria IV Geothermal Power Project.

- Installation of 11/0.415kV auxiliary power for the supply of essential loads within the switch yard.
- Gained thorough knowledge of power and distribution systems and process control and instrumentation
- Isolated faults and resolved electrical system malfunctions of varying degrees of complexity.

**1<sup>st</sup> July to 13<sup>th</sup> September 2013 -** Kenya Ports Authority in the Information Technology Department.

#### **Responsibilities (Intern):**

- Developing and implementing an effective maintenance and service routine for IT equipment i.e. desktops, laptops, scanners and printers.
- Pulling of UTP cable and fiber optic cable (Structured cabling).
- Configuration and troubleshooting on Network RJ45, VHM, HHT and detecting of network failure on faulty cables and wiring closets. Termination of patch cords.

#### **EDUCATION**

- 2009 to 2014 Kenyatta University.
  - ✓ Bsc. Electrical & Electronic Engineering
- 2004 to 2007 Kenyatta High School, Taita.

- ✓ KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION
- ✓ Obtained B plain of 64 points
- 2002 to 2003 Mariakani Garrison Primary School.
  - ✓ KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION
  - ✓ Obtained 380 out of 500 Marks.

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

- 2007(Jan to Nov) Served as the school captain at Kenyatta High School.
- Interest Playing Discus, Driving, playing football, swimming and travelling.

#### **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

April, 2015 – Awarded First Aid at Work certificate by St Johns Ambulance, Kenya

Member of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)

- Student branch.

#### **REFEREES**

ANDREW MWATSUMA MBAJI
KENYA ELECTRICITY GENERATING COMPANY (KENGEN)
P.O. BOX 47936, NAIROBI, KENYA
TEL. +254721885384
Email:andrew.mbaji@gmail.com

Eng. MARTIN M. NZOMO KENYATTA UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY P.O. BOX 43844-00100, NAIROBI, KENYA TEL. +254722516125

Email: mmnzomo@yahoo.com

DAN Ojwang
KENYATTA UNIVERSITY
SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING & TECHNOLOGY
DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL & ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING
P.O. BOX 43844-00100, NAIROBI, KENYA
TEL. +254721336384
Email:ojwang.dan@ku.ac.ke